Guide to the Lantern Slide Collection c. 1860-1942 PR 70
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: General Lantern Slides, 1
  - Massachusetts (Box 42, Item PR-070-0001-0076)
    Spencer-Pierce Little House on Little's Lane, Newbury; Whipple House in Ipswich; Waltham Gore Mansion; Hancock-Clark House in Lexington; "Oak Hill", Peabody; Some of these images may be linked to the George A. Zabriskie lecture entitled "Hightlights of th
  - Massachusetts-Boston, 1910, 1909 (Box 42, Item PR-070-0001-0077)
    Moses-Williams House on Centre St., Jamaica Plain; Faneuil Hall; Union Club, Old South Church; State Capitol; Old South Meeting House; King's Chapel; Boston Public Library; Franklin Statue; Daniel C. Parker House on Beacon St.; Beacon Hill; King's Chapel
  - Massachusetts-Cambridge (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0078)
    John Harvard Statue, Harvard University; Old Elm under which Washington took command; Gore Hall, Library of Harvard University.
  - Massachusetts-Salem (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0079)
    Houses on Chestnut St.; Pierce-Nichols house on Federal St.; Entrance hall to Pierce-Nichols house; Richard Derby house on Derby St.; John Ward House.
  - North America-Mexico (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0080)
    Coal mines in Salinas, Mexico.
  - New Hampshire (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0081)
    Pearson-Woodson House in Portsmouth; Yates doorway on Middle St.; Moffat-Ladd House view from garden.
  - New Jersey (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0082)
    Asbury Park bathers; Ocean Grove; Christ Church, New Brunswick; Nordhof Vreeland house; Burlington "The Old Building" Library; Library Company of Burlington; St. Mary's viewed from woods; Old Kirk Yard at St. Mary's, Burlington; Hamilton Monument, Weehawk
  - New Jersey and New York--Palisades (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0083)
    Views of Palisades, including southern end; view of Palisades Park cliff with trees and fence; Some of these images may be linked to the George A. Zabriskie lecture entitled "Hightlights of the War for -Independence, 1775-1783".
  - New Jersey and New York-Ellis Island--Immigration (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0084)
    Images of men, children and women standing in line with suitcases, as well as sitting at tables with food and looking towards camera.
  - New York and New Jersey--Hudson River, 1874 (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0085)
    Ice-boats sailing on the Hudson River with shoreline in background from London Graphic; Fort Washington Point with lighthouse before bridge was begun; "The Dolphin" ship in Hudson River with land in foreground and rowboat; "Black X Line" ship sailing on
  - New York--Bridges (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0086)
    Poughkeepsie Bridge over Hudson River; unidentified New York Bridge.
  - New York--Churches (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0087)
    Sleepy hollow Dutch Church.
  - New York--Clubs and Organizations, 1907 (Box 43, Item PR-070-0001-0088)
    Oak Point Yacht Club; Wa Wa Yanday Club; Ft. Greene Club; Creedmore Rifle Club.
  - New York--Government and Public Buildings (Box 44, Item PR-070-0001-0089)
    Old Land office on the Bank of Tonawanda; Saratoga Congress; Capitol at Albany; unidentified views.
  - New York--Monuments and Statues (Box 44, Item PR-070-0001-0090)
    Andre Monument in Tarrytown; Some of these images may be linked to the George A. Zabriskie lecture entitled "Hightlights of the War for -Independence, 1775-1783".
  - New York--Museums (Box 44, Item PR-070-0001-0091)
    Suffolk County Historical Society in Riverhead, L.I.; Buffalo Historical Society in Buffalo, N.Y.; House of History--Columbia County Historical Soc. In Kinderhook, N.Y.
  - New York--Parks and Squares (Box 44, Item PR-070-0001-0092)
    Mohawk Lake--Cave Rock; unidentified park views, most probably from New York City; view of man Figure Skating on frozen pond.
  - New York--Residences--Houses and Homes, 1907 (Box 44, 45, Item PR-070-0001-0093)
    Mainly façade views of New York houses, including the Cadwalader home in Colden, N.Y., the Brett Home in Beacon, N.Y., Thomas Cole's studio and house in Catskill, N.Y., workshop and home of Frederic Goudy (including a grounds view), Lewis Delafield home i
  - New York--Streets (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0094)
    Maint Street in Bangor with telephone poles and shops.
  - New York--Transportation (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0095)
    Images of railroad depots and stagecoach stations in Pougkeepsie, Tarrytown, Rhinebeck, Garrison and Amityville as well as several unlabeled views.
  - New York-Albany--Harbors (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0096)
    View of Albany harbor.
  - New York-Highlands (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0097)
    Lower entrance to highlands; view of highlands.
  - New York-Kingston--Government and Public Buildings--Senate House, 1922 (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0098)
    Interior and façade views of Senate House in Kingston; Some of these images may be linked to the George A. Zabriskie lecture entitled "Hightlights of the War for -Independence, 1775-1783".
  - New York-Newburgh--Washington's Headquarters (Box 45, Item PR-070-0001-0099)
    Interior and façade views of Washington's Newburgh headquarters.
  - New York-Niagara Falls (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0100)
    Images of the Niagara Falls from a suspension bridge, and otherwise.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0101)
    Kings Bridge over Spuyten Duyvil Creek showing carriage and buildings in background; Queensboro (or Blackwell's Island) Bridge being built showing East River and Roosevelt Island; Willis Avenue Bridge over Harlem River showing trolley buses and pedestrian
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Brooklyn Bridge, 1876 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0102)
    Views of the Brooklyn Bridge under construction from bridge tower, and finished from South St. dock area.; Views of East River with steamships to south and north from Brooklyn Bridge; Manhattan cityscapes from Brooklyn Bridge, including Woolworth and Muni
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--George Washington Bridge, 1928, 1930 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0103)
    Views of stretching cables for George Washington Bridge and roadway in the making with workers; Aerial views of Manhattan cityscape and New Jersey including George Washington Bridge; coffer dam and George Washington Bridge construction showing Hudson Rive
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Henry Hudson Bridge (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0104)
    Henry Hudson Bridge with steamboats passing underneath; Palisades and Harlem River in background.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--High Bridge (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0105)
    High Bridge with High Bridge Watch Tower in distance, and canoes in Harlem River.; High Bridge with Bronx view and docks; High Bridge with crowded underpass streets and American Flag; View of Harlem River through High Bridge arch; Bronx view with High Bri
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Kissing Bridge, 1860 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0106)
    Kissing Bridge at 2nd Avenue and 52nd Street duplicate transparencies; Views of couples and stream with houses in distance.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Loew Bridge, 1868 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0107)
    Loew Bridge at Broadway looking west on Fulton Street showing St. Paul's Chapel and street scenes. Includes two duplicates. Close-up shot facing north showing pedestrian crossing Loew Bridge.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Macomb's Dam Bridge, 1850, 1904 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0108)
    Macomb's Dam Bridge (a.k.a. Central Bridge) at Jerome Avenue and West 155th Street in the Bronx showing the Harlem River, fishing boats, Washington Bridge, High Bridge and a boathouse.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Stone Bridge, 1800, 1812 (Box 46, Item PR-070-0001-0109)
    Stone Bridge at Canal Street and Broadway showing Stone Bridge Tavern and Garden as well as pedestrians. Three transparencies are copies of a lithograph by George Hayward.
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Third Avenue Bridge (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0110)
    Third Avenue Bridge from Harlem River showing boats and industrial shoreline. Old Third Avenue Bridge from Manhattan showing Bronx in distance and pedestrians in foreground.`
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Washington Bridge, 1861, 1942 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0111)
    Aerial view of Washington Bridge and Harlem River Speedway showing boathouses and shoreline; Aerial view of Washington Bridge showing riverboats and Manhattan and Bronx shorelines; Washington Bridge from Harlem River showing High Bridge; Washington Bridge
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--East River (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0112)
    Image of East River including ships, docks and surrounding buildings.
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--East River--Hellgate, 1842, 1885, 1861 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0113)
    Hellgate from Harlem with sailboats and Bronx houses in distance; large waves with Hellgate Explosions viewed from Harlem with telephone poles and land in foreground; View of Hellgate covered with ice from 86th Street with steamboat, Manhattan snow banks,
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--Harlem River & Ship Canal, 1880, 1760 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0114)
    Harlem River filled with sailboats, steamboats and rowboats on a Saturday afternoon with boathouses on shore; Harlem River at Ship Canal showing industrial area and streets; Harlem River shore north of 3rd Avenue with tugboats, steamboats and industrial b
  - New York-NYC--Topics--Police, 1897 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0115)
    Bicycle Squad, and an image labeled "modern police" with a mounted policeman.
  - New York-NYC--Transportation, 1917, 1869, 1904, 1855, 1880 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0116)
    Horse car to ferries on West Street on cobblestone street showing tracks and surrounding buildings; IRT trial run with city officials and policemen; Boy riding horse away from train caboose--scene shows railroad repairs and cars; Scene of completion of tr
  - New York-NYC--Transportation--Railroad Bridges, 1875-8 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0117)
    Pedestrian Underpass and Long Island Railroad; train shown with pedestrian overpass and snow; N.Y. Central Naduct looking North towards Harlem showing bridge construction and train; Woman on pedestrian footbridge passing over railroad tracks and surrounde
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Churches (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0118)
    Bronx Church House Camp; Summer Gospel Tent.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Clubs and Organizations, 1906, 1894 (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0119)
    McKinley Square Liberty Pole and Flag Association--men sitting on bus with flags, people standing next to bus (including young boy); Suburban Baseball Club--team posing on house front steps in full uniform holding equipment; West Farms Republican Club--si
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Commercial Buildings--Restaurants and Taverns (Box 47, Item PR-070-0001-0120)
    Johnson Tavern in West Farms with telephone poles, fence and weeds; Theo Schoepple Wines and Liquors Store with pedestrian and view of surrounding commercial buildings, as well as telephone poles.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Commercial Buildings--Stores, 1879 ca (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0121)
    John Damm's Cigar shop on Franklin Ave. with family including child on bicycle, mother and wooden Indian in front of store with caged display window; John Michell's Matmaking shop on Centre Street with four men and small child standing on grass in front o
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort No. 4, 1913/02/22 (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0122)
    Fort No.4 in Kingsbridge with snow covered field and fence as well as flagpole.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Industrial Facilities (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0123)
    Ludig's Mill near Bronx River in West Farms (current site of Bronx Park) showing gondola on river and trees.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Monuments and Statues--Tomb of Joseph Rodman Drake (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0124)
    Tomb of Joseph Rodman Drake at Hunt's Point--view of monument surrounded by foliage; view of man standing next to gated monument.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Parades and Processions (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0125)
    Views of unidentified parades, including officials' reviewing stand, marching band, and group of four men standing away from crowd, possibly parade officials; Sunday School parade, including Second Church of the Disciples of Christ, showing children holdi
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Parks and Squares--Bronx Zoo (Box 48, Item PR-070-0001-0126)
    Images of Rocking Stone in Bronx Zoo with man standing nearby and trees in background.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 48, 49, Item PR-070-0001-0127)
    Roberts Homestead with snow and trees--Throggs Neck; Charlton-Ferris House near Old Ferry Point, covered in vines with small boy at front door; Lorrilard Mansion view of house and front yard near Bronx Park; Hunt House, Hunt's Point with snow and American
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes--Poe Cottage, interiors (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0128)
    Sitting room with fireplace and rocking chairs, photographs and rugs; Room with table, chairs, glassware and ivy.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes--Varian House, 1775 (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0129)
    Varian house on Van Cortland and Bainbridge; View of house façade and front lawn with carriages and horses in driveway; drawing of house with pedestrian; Façade view with climbing plants; Side view of house with picket fence.
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Schools and Colleges, 1703 (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0130)
    Fordham College and St. John's College from music sheet showing pedestrians, teachers, students and athletes; Morris High school aerial view showing surrounding rooftops; P.S. 6 on West 177th St. and Vyse Ave. side view with staff and students posing outs
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Streets, 1861 (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0131)
    Marion Ave. and Elm Place with view of houses and firemen from Valentine's Manual; Tinton Ave. view of trees and snow, as well as fences, pedestrian and houses.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Churches (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0132)
    The Tabernacle in Bklyn.; Plymouth Church.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Coney Island--Beaches (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0133)
    Images of men, women and children on beach at Coney Island.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Greene (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0134)
    Flag and steps with pedestrians.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Harbor--Shipbuilding Industry (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0135)
    Empty Brooklyn Dry Dock, Erie Basin, surrounded by industrial buildings.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Monuments and Statues (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0136)
    Prospect Park monument to those killed in Battle of Long Island with view of surrounding area (including Prospect Lake) and man standing in foreground.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Museums (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0137)
    West Brighton Museum--signs for freak show, with men and women lined up outside; next door to pie seller's stand; Eden Musee (wax museum) on Coney Island, with signs for World of Wax; Long Island Historical Society in Brooklyn--façade view.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Parks and Squares--Prospect Park (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0138)
    Images of Japanese Garden with women on footpaths; views of foliage and lakes; Prospect Park sleigh.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Residences--Farms--Remsen Farm House, 1863 (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0139)
    Remsen farm house from Brooklyn Manual, 1863, p. 369 showing fence and farmland, as well as house and shed.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Residences--Houses and Homes, 1700, 1854 (Box 49, Item PR-070-0001-0140)
    Col. Rutgers Residence with view of harbor; Boerum House from Valentine Manual showing façade, yard and fence; Suydam House of Lefferts on Bushwick Lane; Residence of E.C. Litchfield showing façade and front lawn with flag on top of house; Morris Mansion
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Schools and Colleges, 1940 (Item PR-070-0001-0141)
    Vacation Playground at P.S. 45 with view of boys on and around jungle-gym, posing for photograph; P.S. 123 façade view; Girls' rooftop Playground at P.S. 126 showing young girls skipping rope; P.S. 127 façade view; P.S.133 Cooking and House Keeping Class
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Streets--Park Place (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0142)
    View of Park Place covered in snow showing gates and apartment houses in distances, as well as trees.
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Transportation (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0143)
    Forest Park aerial view of train with smoke
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views, 1814 (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0144)
    Views from Tower overlooking Manhattanville; general views of Manhattan with churches and residences, as well as trees and other foliage.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Battery, 1922, 1911, 1856 (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0145)
    Aeroplane view of South Ferry; Birdseye views of lower Manhattan, including Battery; Airplane views of New York Harbor and New York City looking north; Airview of Battery Park looking toward Brooklyn; Lower Manhattan Skyline including ships and airplane,
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Financial District, 1850, 1794, 1922, 1897, 1674 (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0146)
    Broadway & Ann St.; View of (New York, N.Y.) from Mt. Pitt (Clinton and Grand Sts..); Aeroplane views from Bowling Green and Bway looking North; St. Paul Building and St. Paul's Chapel view; Wall & Nassau St.; American Security Building and Trinity Church
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Midtown, 1948, 1922, 1894 (Box 50, Item PR-070-0001-0147)
    Manhattan from Hotel Bossert in Brooklyn Heights, showing Brooklyn docks, East River and Manhattan Harbor; View East from Hudson; View with Grand Central Station (East of Park, North of 38th); Park Ave. north from 39th St. showing skyscrapers; Bway and 6t
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Upper East Side, 1906 (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0148)
    N.E. View of Madison Sq.; Air view looking north from 5th Ave. and 59th St.; View from East River with Roosevelt Island and skyscrapers.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Upper West Side, Heights and Harlems, 1922, 1861, 1904 (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0149)
    Airplane view north from Grant's Tomb showing Hudson River; Airplane view from 110th St. and 8th Ave. looking West; Junction of Bway and 8th Ave.; Morningside Heights north from 120th St. and 118th St.; Kings Pt. St. and St. Andrews--4th Ave. and 128th-12
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Cemeteries (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0150)
    Jewish Cemetery on W. 11th St.; Washington Heights Dyckman Graveyard; St. John's Cemetery on Hudson;; Jewish Cemetery on 6th Ave.; Tomb of Joseph Rodman Drake with high school; 65th St. Cemetery near E. River.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0151)
    St. Peter's church on W. 20th St.; Washington Sq. Church; Private Chapel on 64th St. Jeff. Market Church on 6th Ave.; Church on 23rd St.; St. Phillip's church; Gospel Chapel on 30th St.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Baptist (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0152)
    Baptist Churches on McDougal St, West 3rd St., King St., and West 11th St., including Amity St. Church, Salem Baptist Church, and North Baptist Church.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Baptist, interiors (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0153)
    View of Old North Baptist Church (West 11th St.).
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Catholic (Roman) (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0154)
    St. Patrick's Cathedral; St. John's; St. Peter's Church on Barclay St.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Catholic (Roman), interiors (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0155)
    St. Patrick's Cathedral interior view with altar.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Dutch Reformed (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0156)
    21st Dutch Reformed Church on Bloomingdale; Middle Dutch Church on Lafayette Pl.; Bloomingdale Reformed Church on 68th St. and Bway; Greenwich Dutch Church on Waverly Place; N.W. Dutch Church on 23rd St..
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Dutch Reformed, interiors (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0157)
    Dutch Reform Church on Washington Sq.; Market St. Dutch Church.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--French-German (Huguenot) (Box 51, Item PR-070-0001-0158)
    French-German Tabernacle on Broadway; German Gospel Tabernacle in Chelsea on 36th St. and 10th Ave.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Friends (Quaker) (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0159)
    Quaker Meeting House on Gramercy Sq. (E. 20th St.)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Jewish Synagogues (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0160)
    Temple Beth-el on East 76th St.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Joss Houses (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0161)
    Mott St. Joss House.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Lutheran (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0162)
    Mott St. Lutheran Church (late Episcopal?); St. John's Church on Christopher St..
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Methodist, 1849 (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0163)
    Washington Sq. Methodist Episcopal Church; Chelsea M.E. Church on W. 30th St.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Presbyterian (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0164)
    Rutgers Presbyterian Church (with Hotel Ausmia?) at 73rd and Bway; Shiloh Pres. Church on W. 26th St.; Brick Pres. Church on 5th Ave. and 37th St.; Laight St. Pres. Church; unidentified Pres. church image.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Protestant Episcopal, 1889, 1904 (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0165)
    St. Paul's on Bway; Church of the Ascension on 5th Ave. and 10th St.; Dr. Parkhurst's New Church on Madison Sq.; St. Luke's Church on Hudson St.; St. Patrick's Church on Mott St.; St. Bartholomew's church.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Protestant Episcopal, interiors (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0166)
    St. Paul's Church; unidentified P.E. Church.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unidentified (Box 52, Item PR-070-0001-0167)
    Assorted unidentified Manhattan Churches
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unidentified, interiors (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0168)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unitarian, 1905 (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0169)
    Unit. Church on corner of 20th St. and 4th Ave. near Union Sq.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations, 1830, 1850, 1894/08/23 (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0170)
    View with the National Arts Club building on Gramercy Park South; Façade of The Century Association building on West 43rd Street; Manhattan Athletic Club building at 524 Fifth Avenue; Metropolitan Yacht Club in Harlem at the Peter Randall House with large
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Belvedere Club House, 1792, 1794 (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0171)
    View of Belvedere Club House surrounded by houses, water and ships; Near-duplicates of façade of Belvedere Club House.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Columbia Yacht Club (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0172)
    Blimp and backlit Columbia Yacht Club with telephone wires; Tulips at Columbia Yacht Club with buildings in background.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Metropolitan Club (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0173)
    Hand-painted slide of Metropolitan Club building with red and white striped awnings; Metropolitan Club building with corner of Central Park and carriages. Elbridge T. Gerry's Residence.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Union League Club, 1863 (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0174)
    Drawing of East 17th Street Union League Club House façade; Union League Club Building with buildings, pedestrians and carriages on 39th Street and Fifth Avenue.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0175)
    Consolidated Stock Exchange of New York building on Broad and Beaver Streets with paperboy in front, as well as view of surrounding area and men standing outside building.
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Banks, 1831 (Box 53, Item PR-070-0001-0176)